Guide to the John Kirby Davis Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John Kirby Davis papers
1929-1933
MS 1616
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The papers consist of correspondence, letters of introduction, newspapers clippings, and memorabilia of John Kirby Davis. The majority of the correspondence is to family members and concerns personal matters and the 1929 Depression.
Davis, John Kirby, 1901-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Maura Hametz Webb, 1991.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
John Kirby Davis was born February 4, 1901, in Denver, Colorado. Before entering Yale, Davis attended St. Andrews. As a Yale student, he was a member of the Freshman Football Squad, and of the Varsity Football Squad in 1921 and 1922; a member of the Track Team in 1922; and was on the Freshman Wrestling Team. He won his "Y" in track.
From 1923 to 1928 Davis was associated with the American Optical Company, Southbridge, Massachusetts. In 1929 he joined Colonial Western Airways, Inc., as District Manager for Rochester, New York. In 1938 Davis was a Research Executive with Barrington Associations in New York City.
During the war Davis served as a Lieutenant in the Navy and was stationed for a time at the U.S. Naval Air Station, Lake City, Florida. In August, 1946, he was released to inactive duty.
Taken from: The Class of Nineteen Twenty-Three Yearbook and The Quarter Century Chronicle.
For additional biographical information, see reunion volumes for the class of 1923.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, letters of introduction, newspapers clippings, and memorabilia of John Kirby Davis. The majority of the correspondence is to family members and concerns personal matters and the 1929 Depression.
Depressions -- 1929 -- United States; United States -- Social conditions -- 1918-1932; Davis, John Kirby, 1901-; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1923
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  The John K. Davis Papers consist of personal correspondence, printed material, and memorabilia.
  The papers were the gift of Maura Hametz Webb in 1990.
  - Correspondence
    - C -D, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Davis, Ada (Cafagna) (wife), undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Davis, Carl Raymond (father), 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Foreman, Eunice (Armstrong), 1932, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - G -J, 1932-1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - M -S, 1932-1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - [Stower?], Peg (Mrs. M. B.) (aunt), 1932, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Tolson, Lil, 1932-1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - W, 1931-1932, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wells, Albert (uncle), 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Wells, Celie, 1933 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Wells, Channing, 1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Wells, Ethel B. (Mrs. Albert), 1932-1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Wells, George B. (cousin), 1932-1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified, 1931-1933, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1932, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Student pilot permit and daily log, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 17)